<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mac on Voxcaster</title>
    <link>http://vox.me.uk/tags/mac/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mac on Voxcaster</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 08:42:24 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://vox.me.uk/tags/mac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Issues With MacOS</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/06/issues-with-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 08:42:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/06/issues-with-macos/</guid>
      <description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been running in to issues with macOS that I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to resolve and it&amp;rsquo;s beginning to annoy me no end.
Startup I&amp;rsquo;d been running in to startup issues for a week or so - the Mac would boot up and I would see the Apple logo on screen with the loading bar.
However, the screen would then go blank and I would only see the mouse cursor if I wriggled it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colours for Hue</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/05/colours-for-hue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 19:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/05/colours-for-hue/</guid>
      <description>Colours For Hue Getting Hue lights has meant that I need to control these. Generally, this works well using the Hue application and Siri (with HomeKit), though as I’ve got one in my office as well, it would be nice to control this from my Mac as well.
This is where Colours for Hue comes in. It’s a Mac app that sits in the menu bar and acts as a Hue light controller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shush</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/03/shush/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 19:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/03/shush/</guid>
      <description>Shush As Covid 19 spreads around the globe and countries go in to lockdown and work from home, I’ve had to do more and more meetings online.
When I’ve done online meetings in the past, I’ve had to do them either via conference call or via the conferencing setup at work, and therefore on Windows. They’ve generally worked OK.
However, as we’re all currently confined to working from home in the UK, I’ve been using my Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
