<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Keyboard on Voxcaster</title>
    <link>http://vox.me.uk/tags/keyboard/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Keyboard on Voxcaster</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 09:10:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://vox.me.uk/tags/keyboard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Matias Quiet Pro Keyboard</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2022/01/matias-quiet-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 09:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2022/01/matias-quiet-pro/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been playing about with new keyboards over the last few months - my most recent purchase is the Matias Quiet Pro for the Mac.
This is an American layout board that works with Bluetooth on the Mac and has a Mac based layout. It uses quiet Alps based keyswitches, rather than any of the Cherry MX or Cherry based knockoffs.
Quality The device feels sturdy enough when being used. However, there are some aspects that make it feel a bit cheaper than it should.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keychron Keyboard</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/04/keychron-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 10:46:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/04/keychron-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>With lockdown continuing in the UK, and working from home, I decided to look once more at the mechanical keyboard market.
I had been using the Logitech K350 on Windows without any issues, but for whatever reason, I wasn’t able to use this nicely on the Mac - I’d often get drop outs or lag, where what I was typing wasn’t picked up, or was lost completely 1.
In the mean time, I’d been using a Windows Dell keyboard - a cheap and cheerful keyboard that did the job, and I actually wasn’t getting RSI by using it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheap Mechanical Keyboard</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/04/cheap-mechanical-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 19:45:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/04/cheap-mechanical-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>Cheap Mechanical Keyboard So I&amp;rsquo;ve been a fan of mechanical keyboards for a while - I&amp;rsquo;ve purchased a number of the years. The best one that I&amp;rsquo;ve used to date is the Matias Tactile Pro but that died after a few years of use, but I&amp;rsquo;ve also tried some of the other ones on the market. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really have a preference in terms of switches, but I&amp;rsquo;d tried the Matias ones, and quite liked them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPad Magic Keyboard</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/05/ipad-magic-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 19:56:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/05/ipad-magic-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>iPad Magic Keyboard I tried using the keyboard and mouse with my iPad for a while to see how the iPad could cope with being a laptop replacement.
I concluded that I wouldn’t get the Magic Keyboard. However, here I am, typing this blog post on it.
Many people have already written reviews, so I’m a bit late to the game - they’ve pretty much given their opinion on it, and there isn’t a huge amount more I could add.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
