<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GPS on Voxcaster</title>
    <link>http://vox.me.uk/tags/gps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GPS on Voxcaster</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 19:31:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://vox.me.uk/tags/gps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GPS Accuracy</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/02/gps-accuracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 19:31:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/02/gps-accuracy/</guid>
      <description>GPS Accuracy After a recent walk, I decided to analyse the data from the Garmin FIT files - one from my eTrex 25 and the other from my Apple Watch 4 and iPhone XR. I was purely interested in seeing how well the Garmin eTrex 25 was able to act as a tracker - mainly as when I was using it for my geocaching walk, it seemed to be tracking me, but looked on the screen to be sticking purely to the paths in the grounds of Wollaton Hall, which was a bit surprising.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TALBOL Geocaching Series</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2018/08/talbol-geocaching-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 11:41:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2018/08/talbol-geocaching-series/</guid>
      <description>With some spare time at the weekend, I thought that I would get some practise in for my LEL award and I wanted to team this up with a geocaching trail that I&amp;rsquo;d seen. This way, I could go out and enjoy a day hike, whilst getting in some geocaching.
Route I&amp;rsquo;d done some hikes in the Peak District for cadets recently and had seen a number of caches with the acronym TAL - on a bit of digging, this appears to be short for The Alien Landings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geocaching</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2018/07/geocaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 10:13:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2018/07/geocaching/</guid>
      <description>My cycling has seemed to have dropped off somewhat since moving to Manchester. A downside to moving away from the London Brompton Club perhaps as I&amp;rsquo;ve not found a club up here that I&amp;rsquo;ve fancied doing much riding with as it&amp;rsquo;s not quite as welcoming and social as the LBC has been. I think that also weekend training exercises with cadets isn&amp;rsquo;t helpful to getting rides in at the weekend either!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
