<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Voxcaster</title>
    <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Voxcaster</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 08:22:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://vox.me.uk/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Garmin Venu 2 Review</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2022/02/garmin-venu-2-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 08:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2022/02/garmin-venu-2-review/</guid>
      <description>When I saw this announced by Garmin, I knew that it was something that I’d be interested in. I’ve flip flopped between Garmin and the Apple Watch over the last two years, often coming back to my Garmin Instinct Solar (and the non solar version before that). However, the reason for going back and testing the Apple Watch was for the onboard Siri support - being able to turn lights on and off in the house with my voice is handy, as well as the occasional quick text message or receiving a phone call whilst my phone is in my bike bag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Varia Radar Light</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2022/01/varia-radar-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 09:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2022/01/varia-radar-light/</guid>
      <description>It’s been on my wish list for a while, but I finally purchased a Varia Radar Light (Varia RTL515) recently from Amazon, as it was on offer.
However, I didn’t keep it very long and it was used for a day before returning.
Perhaps I was expecting too much of it or that my use case wasn’t the best example of it.
Radar The light uses radar to detect cars behind you and alert you to the fact on your head unit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matias Quiet Pro Keyboard</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2022/01/matias-quiet-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 09:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2022/01/matias-quiet-pro/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been playing about with new keyboards over the last few months - my most recent purchase is the Matias Quiet Pro for the Mac.
This is an American layout board that works with Bluetooth on the Mac and has a Mac based layout. It uses quiet Alps based keyswitches, rather than any of the Cherry MX or Cherry based knockoffs.
Quality The device feels sturdy enough when being used. However, there are some aspects that make it feel a bit cheaper than it should.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor Control</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2022/01/monitor-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 07:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2022/01/monitor-control/</guid>
      <description>I’ve got a Mac Mini and this is hooked up to a LG 27UL850-W and Dell S2421NX monitor. They’re both setup on my desk, with the LG as my main monitor and the Dell as a secondary monitor off to the side.
When using the desktop, I’ve always missed the ability to adjust the screen brightness easily within macOS using the keyboard, like you can on the MacBook and generally any Windows laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search for Windows Alfred</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/12/windows-alfred/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 16:21:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/12/windows-alfred/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been mixing macOS and Windows for a number of years. This hasn&amp;rsquo;t normally proved to be problematic in any way and I&amp;rsquo;ve had the best of both worlds.
One program that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t live with out on the Mac is Alfred. Alfred is a keyboard launcher, allowing you to start and run programs using a key combination and not having to move away from the keyboard. It also provides a quick calculation tool, which allows you to undertake calculations quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bear for Blogging</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/10/bear-for-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 15:30:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/10/bear-for-blogging/</guid>
      <description>I had ditched Ulysses when it went subscription but during 2020, I’d paid for the subscription as I’d managed to get a discount code for it. It was good to be able to use it across my devices and it’s still one of the best plain text editors in my view - however, I don’t view it as being worth almost £50 a year - consider that Microsoft charge £60 for Office plus storage space, whereas Ulysses makes use of iCloud space to sync, so I’m not even paying them for syncing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email and Hook</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/09/email-and-hook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 20:51:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/09/email-and-hook/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d been looking at my email clients on the Mac for using with Hook. I like the ability to link any previous email, as it helps me link to emails I&amp;rsquo;ve received or sent within my Obsidian notebook, and to be honest, it&amp;rsquo;s paid off a number of times now where it was quicker to look for the specific email that I&amp;rsquo;d linked in my Obsidian notebook, rather than search for the email I needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keychron Keyboard</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/04/keychron-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 10:46:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/04/keychron-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>With lockdown continuing in the UK, and working from home, I decided to look once more at the mechanical keyboard market.
I had been using the Logitech K350 on Windows without any issues, but for whatever reason, I wasn’t able to use this nicely on the Mac - I’d often get drop outs or lag, where what I was typing wasn’t picked up, or was lost completely 1.
In the mean time, I’d been using a Windows Dell keyboard - a cheap and cheerful keyboard that did the job, and I actually wasn’t getting RSI by using it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance per Watt</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/04/performance-per-watt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 09:34:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/04/performance-per-watt/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to compare the performance per watt of the new M1 Mac mini against that of my Ryzen 1600X powered gaming PC. To throw some additional items in there, I also measured my Ryzen 4300U little Windows office PC as well and my Raspberry Pi 4.
The speed of the new M1 Mac has shown that Apple’s move to Apple Silicon has been a good move for them. Benchmarks show that it’s faster than some of the Intel and AMD machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RAID 0 QNAP</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/03/qnap-raid-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 15:20:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/03/qnap-raid-0/</guid>
      <description>I’d posted about my QNAP TR-002 previously and how I was using it as direct attached storage for my Mac. Recently, I moved it to the PC to use it as storage for gaming, as I’d switched my Mac external storage to a Samsung T7 external drive.
For the gaming rig, I added a second 3TB drive to the TR-002 and used reformatted to NTFS. RAID 0 should give me some additional speeds over the storage I was currently using.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FDS on the M1 Mac</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/01/fds-m1-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 10:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/01/fds-m1-mac/</guid>
      <description>So whenever I get a new machine, I always run an FDS benchmark on it - purely for fun and comparative purposes. I’ll often run it, even on a machine that isn’t likely to run FDS in a normal situations, such as the M1T Mini PC and Raspberry Pi.
So with the M1 Mac Mini, there was no reason not to run the benchmarks as well. However, as the M1 Mac is based on an ARM based chip, I wasn’t expecting it to perform that well - after all, it would be running on the Mac using Rosetta 2, as FDS is compiled for x86 processors1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synology Issues</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/01/synology-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 10:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/01/synology-issues/</guid>
      <description>I ran in to some issues with my Synology over the Christmas period, involving BTRFS and RAID.
I had been running the NAS with an 8TB hard drive for main storage and a 3TB drive aimed at backups. However, I’d noticed a lot of a files deleted a few weeks ago which made me uneasy and then recently I found a corrupt image file on my gaming rig.
I wasn’t sure if this was the fault of the desktop, or the Synology, but when I investigated the Synology, I found that the BTRFS file system I was using to help protect against bit rot wasn’t actually protecting me at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QNAP TR 002 DAS</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/01/qnap-tr-002-das/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 14:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/01/qnap-tr-002-das/</guid>
      <description>With the recent purchase of the Mac Mini, I needed to have an external drive - partly for Time Machine backups and partly as I only went 256GB internal drive. I’d got a couple of 2.5” hard drive caddies lying around, but also a 3.5” drive that wasn’t being used. Teamed up with the reduced number of ports on the M1 Mac Mini, I decided that I’d purchase a Direct Attached Storage (DAS) device for the Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M1 Mac Mini</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/01/m1-mac-mini/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 18:59:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/01/m1-mac-mini/</guid>
      <description>After the issues I’ve had previously with the Mac, I wasn’t sure I was going to get another Mac. But I did.
I watched the M1 release keynote after it had finished and was impressed with what I saw. If it was true. However, after hanging around the Mac Power Users forum, I’d seen some interesting Mac apps that I fancied giving a go - things like Hook. I also wanted to continue using Photos, as I hadn’t really found an alternative on Windows that really matched it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insync</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/12/insync/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 15:49:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/12/insync/</guid>
      <description>My current job sees me using Onedrive as the primary storage location for files, and since the initial lockdown in the UK, we moved to using Microsoft Teams and storing data in Teams instead, rather than our on site servers and mapped hard drives.
This took some getting used to but suited me, as it meant that I could use my Mac Mini at home to access the files and work, rather than a work machine, which was good, as I had forgone the standard laptops that everyone else used so I could have an iPad for carrying out my risk assessments on, but this obviously isn&amp;rsquo;t as good for general office tasks1!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motion and Live Photos</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/11/motion-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 12:10:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/11/motion-photos/</guid>
      <description>Apple&amp;rsquo;s Live Photos and Android equivalent, Motion Photos, initially seemed a bit like a gimmick when they were announced. However, there are a number of times now where the Live Photos on the iPhone has been of good use - mainly to capture amusing antics before or after the photo occurred!
With playing with Android, I was surprised that this didn&amp;rsquo;t appear to have the same. However, after some googling, I discovered it does, and it&amp;rsquo;s called Motion Photos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking ARM</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/11/benchmarking-arm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 10:28:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/11/benchmarking-arm/</guid>
      <description>There has been much talk on how well ARM processors have moved on and how they can potentially now compete with x86-64 chips. Even though Microsoft have launched the Surface Pro X, which uses an ARM chip and Apple are moving the Mac&amp;rsquo;s to ARM processors, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t really considered just how far they&amp;rsquo;d come.
I&amp;rsquo;ve had a Raspberry Pi and various versions since they were released and have been able to adequately use the Pi3+ for minimal desktop use and I&amp;rsquo;ve had the iPad Pro for work for a number of years as well, which has performed quite well, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never really put two and two together on how well they compared to the X86 chips I have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows 10 DPI Scaling</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/11/windows-10-dpi-scaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 13:33:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/11/windows-10-dpi-scaling/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve resisted the high DPI screens for Windows machines for a number of years - mainly due to the cost of the screens. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve since upgraded a number of items and they now have larger screens.
My monitor is now a Dell S2719DC 27&amp;quot; which has a display of 2560 x 1440 and my Surface Pro 7 has a resolution of 2736 x 1824. Both of which require some Windows scaling to adequately use from my point of view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pixel 3a vs IPhone SE</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/10/pixel-3a-vs-iphone-se/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 18:36:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/10/pixel-3a-vs-iphone-se/</guid>
      <description>So, the iPhone SE was re-released, perhaps as a way for Apple to compete with the cheaper Android devices out there. Google started something similar last year with the release of the Pixel 3a - a cheaper, less powerful version of the Pixel 3.
I&amp;rsquo;ve tried both phones - I own the Pixel 3a and my wife has the iPhone SE 2020, so thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a quick review.
Camera The Pixel series is known for its camera, and the iPhone has always been well regarded for its camera - with Apple pushing the camera features heavily in various advertising.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspire Continued</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/10/inspire-continued/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 20:58:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/10/inspire-continued/</guid>
      <description>After some further experimentation and use, I’ve a few more comments on Inspire Writer. I have been initially impressed with the Windows Ulysses clone. My initial review was written in it and was written using the 10 day free trial period. I purchased the software after using it for a day on the Windows Store - so I’ve been using the Microsoft Store version. There is a stand alone version available as well, though I would hope that there is feature parity between the two.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Journaling</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/10/markdown-journaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 16:41:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/10/markdown-journaling/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been journaling now for years. I started off using Day One for iOS and macOS. However, after this updated to the second version and moved to a subscription model, I decided that I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to pay for it, and moved. Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Zim Wiki for my journaling.
This has generally served me well, and ran nicely on Windows and Linux1. It worked and the output was portable and under my control, as each page is a text file and displays images inline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Synology</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/09/new-synology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 19:54:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/09/new-synology/</guid>
      <description>With the lockdown and working from home more often, I decided that my Synology (DS 116) was due for an upgrade. I wanted to retire one of my Raspberry Pi&amp;rsquo;s that was running my Pi Hole server and I wanted to have a play with some of the features on the higher end Synology&amp;rsquo;s - such as virtual machines and Docker, as well as make use of the BTRFS file system, so that meant getting one of the Intel Atom powered Synology devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>File Juggler</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/09/file-juggler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 12:36:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/09/file-juggler/</guid>
      <description>One of the programs on macOS that I felt was missing on Windows was an alternative for Hazel. I spent ages looking around for an alternative, and the best I could find for a while was DropIt! The only issue with this is that DropIt is a bit more of a manual process in comparison to Hazel, as you have to drag and drop files into the program for them to be sorted1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OxiPNG and Pngout</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/08/oxipng-and-pngout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 07:52:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/08/oxipng-and-pngout/</guid>
      <description>One thing that had stuck with me from reading Coding Horror, is that you can increase the speed of your website with free bandwidth. In fairness, it&amp;rsquo;s not free bandwidth, it&amp;rsquo;s reducing the file size of the files that you&amp;rsquo;re hosting, so it&amp;rsquo;s faster to download. The Zopfli article above is the more recent one - the first was regarding pngout (article).
Both pngout and zopfli can reduce the size of files - specifically in this case, PNG files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows PowerToys</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/08/windows-powertoys/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 08:25:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/08/windows-powertoys/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft are making use of their purchase of Github to host the source for their ongoing work in to Powertoys.
PowerToys is a collection of applications that perform a range of different tasks that users may need to undertake regularly. There&amp;rsquo;s an Image Resizer that hooks in to the right click menu, there&amp;rsquo;s fancy zones, which expands upon Windows snap, by adding zones to snap to.
However, the big draw for me is PowerToys Run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auf Wiedersehen Dropbox</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/08/auf_wiedersehen_dropbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 16:51:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/08/auf_wiedersehen_dropbox/</guid>
      <description>So, a few years back, I almost moved away from Dropbox. In fact, I generally got away without using Dropbox at all, which worked out nicely. However, I went back and for a while, I&amp;rsquo;ve also had Dropbox lurking away on my system.
That is until today where I fell foul of the three device limit. On the free, basic tier, Dropbox only permits three devices to be used. This hadn&amp;rsquo;t effected me, as for the past year and a bit, I had my personal account linked to my Pro, office account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Watch Background</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/07/apple-watch-background/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 11:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/07/apple-watch-background/</guid>
      <description>Apple Watch Faces I’ve been playing around with some Apple Watch faces recently - normally I would use a Modular Infographic face or at least one with a number of complications. However, I saw this one which I thought was a bit of fun.
As I’m going through a Star Wars phase again at the minute, I thought this was a good one.
I found the original artist here where you can download the image yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issues With MacOS</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/06/issues-with-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 08:42:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/06/issues-with-macos/</guid>
      <description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been running in to issues with macOS that I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to resolve and it&amp;rsquo;s beginning to annoy me no end.
Startup I&amp;rsquo;d been running in to startup issues for a week or so - the Mac would boot up and I would see the Apple logo on screen with the loading bar.
However, the screen would then go blank and I would only see the mouse cursor if I wriggled it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhotoSync, Photos and iCloud</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/06/photosync-photos-and-icloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 15:31:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/06/photosync-photos-and-icloud/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been a fan of PhotoSync for a while now - I purchased the iOS version in May 2018, so I’ve been using it for 2 years. I’ve also purchased the Android version and it’s one of the key apps I’ve used regularly.
Prior to finding it, I’d been using Dropbox to save a copy of my photos off my phone. This worked well, and the only reason I changed to PhotoSync was that I could choose different locations to send data (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PDF Expert vs PDF XChange</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/06/pdf-expert-vs-pdf-xchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 15:00:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/06/pdf-expert-vs-pdf-xchange/</guid>
      <description>I work in engineering - one of the main formats that gets shared around a lot is the humble PDF. It often means that you can view exactly what the other person sees without the hassle of sharing additional items - I&amp;rsquo;m thinking CAD files here, where an architect may include a lot of references to external files within the CAD file that matches what the architect uses on the system, but won&amp;rsquo;t be installed in the same location or at all, on the clients machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheap Mechanical Keyboard</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/04/cheap-mechanical-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 19:45:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/04/cheap-mechanical-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>Cheap Mechanical Keyboard So I&amp;rsquo;ve been a fan of mechanical keyboards for a while - I&amp;rsquo;ve purchased a number of the years. The best one that I&amp;rsquo;ve used to date is the Matias Tactile Pro but that died after a few years of use, but I&amp;rsquo;ve also tried some of the other ones on the market. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really have a preference in terms of switches, but I&amp;rsquo;d tried the Matias ones, and quite liked them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPad Magic Keyboard</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/05/ipad-magic-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 19:56:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/05/ipad-magic-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>iPad Magic Keyboard I tried using the keyboard and mouse with my iPad for a while to see how the iPad could cope with being a laptop replacement.
I concluded that I wouldn’t get the Magic Keyboard. However, here I am, typing this blog post on it.
Many people have already written reviews, so I’m a bit late to the game - they’ve pretty much given their opinion on it, and there isn’t a huge amount more I could add.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colours for Hue</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/05/colours-for-hue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 19:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/05/colours-for-hue/</guid>
      <description>Colours For Hue Getting Hue lights has meant that I need to control these. Generally, this works well using the Hue application and Siri (with HomeKit), though as I’ve got one in my office as well, it would be nice to control this from my Mac as well.
This is where Colours for Hue comes in. It’s a Mac app that sits in the menu bar and acts as a Hue light controller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philips Hue</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/05/philips-hue/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 19:53:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/05/philips-hue/</guid>
      <description>Philips Hue I’ve had a number of smart items around the house now for a few years. These have mainly been the TP-Link smart plugs, but I’d also got two Elgato Eve smart plugs and a single TP-Link bulb.
In general, these have been OK, though they don’t all link together - TP-Link is controlled through its Kasa platform (and works with Alexa) but the Elgato plugs only work with Apple HomeKit and therefore have to be operated using our phones only (no HomePod).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keyboard and Mouse with the iPad</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/04/keyboard-and-mouse-with-the-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 19:51:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/04/keyboard-and-mouse-with-the-ipad/</guid>
      <description>Keyboard and Mouse with the iPad So, I’ve been playing around with the keyboard and mouse for the iPad Pro after Apple brought out the support for it in iPad OS 13.4.
I’ve been using the Filco 2 Tenkeyless Convertible keyboard and a Logitech MX Master mouse and have been using it on and off over the past week or so.
The whole intention of this is to consider if it’s worth purchasing the £300 iPad Magic with a touchpad keyboard for the iPad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outlook for Mac</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/04/outlook-for-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 19:49:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/04/outlook-for-mac/</guid>
      <description>Outlook for Mac One of the aspects that I thought would be good about working from home on the lockdown has come from being able to use my Mac. I’ve been able to use my Mac to do all things that I’d have to do on my Windows machine at work and it’s really given me a chance to see how the Mac would be able to perform my day to day job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspire Writer</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/04/inspire-writer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 19:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/04/inspire-writer/</guid>
      <description>Inspire Writer I&amp;rsquo;d been tossing up about purchasing a subscription to Ulysses on the Mac or not this year. In the end, I did and I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it for the last couple of blog posts that I&amp;rsquo;ve written. However, I&amp;rsquo;m not always on the Mac - I&amp;rsquo;m often on Windows and I miss using it when I am using Windows.
I&amp;rsquo;d been looking around for ages to find something that replicated it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iCaching - macOS Review</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/04/icaching-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 19:43:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/04/icaching-review/</guid>
      <description>iCaching - macOS Review I’ve been geocaching for a few years now and I’ve been using Geocaching Swiss Army Knife (GSAK) for the past year. It’s a handy program for keeping track of caches that I’ve found, as well as organising GPX files for import on to my Garmin or phone.
However, the program is Windows only. Which isn’t the end of the world, as I have a Windows machine, but I’ve also got a Mac and it tends to be my main machine for getting work done at home, so it’s often on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shush</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/03/shush/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 19:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/03/shush/</guid>
      <description>Shush As Covid 19 spreads around the globe and countries go in to lockdown and work from home, I’ve had to do more and more meetings online.
When I’ve done online meetings in the past, I’ve had to do them either via conference call or via the conferencing setup at work, and therefore on Windows. They’ve generally worked OK.
However, as we’re all currently confined to working from home in the UK, I’ve been using my Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geocaching Trip</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/02/geocaching-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 19:35:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/02/geocaching-trip/</guid>
      <description>Geocaching trip A quick geocaching trip seemed to be in order this weekend to grab the new souvenir that was released for palindrome day.
To get the souvenir, only a single geocache was needed, and that was initially all I decided to head out to get, but as I planned it, I ended up thinking I could do a nice loop and get more than just a single cache. It would also be a chance to get out and explore the local area by bike, so that&amp;rsquo;s what I did.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPS Accuracy</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/02/gps-accuracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 19:31:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/02/gps-accuracy/</guid>
      <description>GPS Accuracy After a recent walk, I decided to analyse the data from the Garmin FIT files - one from my eTrex 25 and the other from my Apple Watch 4 and iPhone XR. I was purely interested in seeing how well the Garmin eTrex 25 was able to act as a tracker - mainly as when I was using it for my geocaching walk, it seemed to be tracking me, but looked on the screen to be sticking purely to the paths in the grounds of Wollaton Hall, which was a bit surprising.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Watch Step Counter</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/01/apple-watch-step-counter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 12:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/01/apple-watch-step-counter/</guid>
      <description>Apple Watch Step Counter One of things I&amp;rsquo;ve found missing from the Apple Watch is the ability to display your steps for the day. The Apple Watch does have the ring system - something that I&amp;rsquo;ve found to be generally better than the Garmin system as Garmin only tracks intensity minutes and steps but occasionally it&amp;rsquo;s nice to check my step count for the day. After all, the watch tracks the steps you take during the day, it seems odd that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t display it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 Geocaching</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2019/01/2018-geocaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 16:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2019/01/2018-geocaching/</guid>
      <description>So 2018 was pretty much the year I started geocaching and it&amp;rsquo;s been a good year - however, we&amp;rsquo;ll see if 2019 can beat 2018!
Avro Round Walk The first day of my Christmas holiday saw me undertake the Avro Round geocache route around the old Avro factory and airfield in Poynton. It was a bit of a muddy walk in fairness as the image below shows!
It was a nice route, especially as it was aviation themed (and builders of the two most recognisable British bombers, the Vulcan and Lancaster).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brompton in Switzerland</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2018/12/brompton-in-switzerland/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 14:41:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2018/12/brompton-in-switzerland/</guid>
      <description>At the end of November, I had to go to Geneva for work - a one day workshop at CERN on fire risk. Considering it was the area I completed my PhD in and work were paying, what was not to like?
Anyhow, after some serious thought, I decided that I&amp;rsquo;d take my Brompton with me to Switzerland and that I&amp;rsquo;d enjoy some cycling around Geneva collecting some geocaches. I say serious thought, as it would mean that I would have to pay the Easyjet baggage fee to get there and back again!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitlocker vs Cryptomator</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2018/12/bitlocker-vs-cryptomator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 21:58:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2018/12/bitlocker-vs-cryptomator/</guid>
      <description>I carry around a USB drive with me - usually a Sandisk Ultra USB, but occasionally a SSD drive1. It usually comes in handy, as I either want to carry around my documents and images or need to transfer files between devices. However, the most common use, is for work files so that I can edit/continue working whilst I&amp;rsquo;m away from the office and I cannot connect to the VPN or to overcome the poor VPN speeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NValt on Windows</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2018/12/nvalt-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 21:49:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2018/12/nvalt-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>One of the few programs I really miss from macOS is nValt. I used that (rather than Notational Velocity) for a number of years for storing notes and stored everything in it from blog posts, to research notes and paper reviews. It worked well and I preferred it to Evernote.
Since then however, I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered Zim Wiki and I use that for storing my data that where I may need images, as at the end of the day, it saves data as a text file still, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to access it at a later date wherever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zim Journal Continued</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2018/09/zim-journal-continued/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 16:49:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2018/09/zim-journal-continued/</guid>
      <description>Zim is a notebook type software - think Evernote or Onenote. However, it&amp;rsquo;s free and open source and saves data locally. It also saves all files as plain text, so you can access the files however and wherever you want.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it for a journal for a period of about three years now and I&amp;rsquo;ve written about it before. I did for a time switch back to Day One and tried the new syncing service, but when they had syncing issues earlier this year which exposed private data, I made sure I was back using Zim (syncing between my devices with Resilo Sync and stored on my own devices).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TALBOL Geocaching Series</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2018/08/talbol-geocaching-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 11:41:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2018/08/talbol-geocaching-series/</guid>
      <description>With some spare time at the weekend, I thought that I would get some practise in for my LEL award and I wanted to team this up with a geocaching trail that I&amp;rsquo;d seen. This way, I could go out and enjoy a day hike, whilst getting in some geocaching.
Route I&amp;rsquo;d done some hikes in the Peak District for cadets recently and had seen a number of caches with the acronym TAL - on a bit of digging, this appears to be short for The Alien Landings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geocaching</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2018/07/geocaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 10:13:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2018/07/geocaching/</guid>
      <description>My cycling has seemed to have dropped off somewhat since moving to Manchester. A downside to moving away from the London Brompton Club perhaps as I&amp;rsquo;ve not found a club up here that I&amp;rsquo;ve fancied doing much riding with as it&amp;rsquo;s not quite as welcoming and social as the LBC has been. I think that also weekend training exercises with cadets isn&amp;rsquo;t helpful to getting rides in at the weekend either!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Plug Showdown</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2018/01/smart-plug-showdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 17:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2018/01/smart-plug-showdown/</guid>
      <description>Intro I&amp;rsquo;ve recently started using smart plugs throughout the home - initially stemming from the fact that I bought a TP-Link HS110 because I wanted to measure the charging rate and total capacity of my new plug-in hybrid. However, after using it for a while, I found I was using it more and more elsewhere within the house (or knew of locations I could use it) so I bought myself a few of the cheaper models (HS100 - the same plug but with no power monitoring).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Brompton</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2017/07/new-brompton/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 19:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2017/07/new-brompton/</guid>
      <description>I’ve had my Brompton Loki for over three years now. It has served me well. However, it’s had a number of changes to it since owning it after I figured out what I wanted:
  A dynamo and lights were fitted. The Shimano hub and lights have served me well, but made things easier in terms of lighting - I was never left without lights if I had gone out and I don’t have to worry about batteries at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin Cycling Again</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2017/05/berlin-cycling-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 19:58:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2017/05/berlin-cycling-again/</guid>
      <description>The past few days I&amp;rsquo;ve been travelling around Europe - through Amsterdam and Berlin. I decided to do the same cycle tour as I&amp;rsquo;d previously done when I was in Berlin two years ago. I&amp;rsquo;d done it before but I did enjoy it, and whilst the sights I would see again would be the same, I would have a different tour guide and therefore the tour would be slightly different. Eileen had also never seen the sights, so doing it with her would give us the chance to see things together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPad Laptop</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2017/05/ipad-laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 16:57:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2017/05/ipad-laptop/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been on holiday and decided that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t take my laptop with me, I&amp;rsquo;d stick with my iPad Mini. I felt that I&amp;rsquo;d be able to do everything I needed to with just iOS.
Turns out, I&amp;rsquo;m not far wrong.
Keyboard Perhaps the biggest bugbear was the keyboard. I&amp;rsquo;ve got the Logitech Keys-to-go and whilst it&amp;rsquo;s small and lightweight, I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of using it. I&amp;rsquo;ve found that I have to hit the keys quite hard to get them to register and that isn&amp;rsquo;t that comfy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac Mini SSD</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2017/04/mac-mini-ssd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 21:22:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2017/04/mac-mini-ssd/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s clear that SSD&amp;rsquo;s are far faster than their mechanical counterparts. Using a computer with a spinning hard drive after you&amp;rsquo;ve been used to an SSD can be tantamount to torture. Sure, it works, but sitting there waiting for items to load can be real drag. One of the worst contenders I&amp;rsquo;ve seen is Atom (or Outlook if you happen to be using my work laptop - that is SLOW to load).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iCloud Online</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2017/03/icloud-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 10:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2017/03/icloud-online/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve sold my Mac and have been relying on Windows and Linux - almost a year has gone by since I got rid of the MacBook Pro. I&amp;rsquo;ve not really missed it since it&amp;rsquo;s been gone. In general, I&amp;rsquo;ve been well served by my Windows gaming rig and my Lenovo X220 laptop running Xubuntu.
In fact, I&amp;rsquo;ve tended to prefer open source software and my Xubuntu laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rack Bag Purchase</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2017/02/rack-bag-purchase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 20:34:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2017/02/rack-bag-purchase/</guid>
      <description>Rack Bag A few weeks back, I looked into how I was going to carry around my spare inner tubes and pump on my cyclocross bike, especially after I&amp;rsquo;ve ended up with two punctures on the cyclocross bike! Part of that was to move the Carradice saddlebag I used on my commuter onto the Verenti and to find another solution for the Dawes.
In the end, I settled for a rack bag, as I thought that with the rack on there, it made sense to have a bag that didn&amp;rsquo;t leave the rack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Bike Parts</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2017/02/new-bike-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 10:07:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2017/02/new-bike-parts/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up some new bike bits over the Christmas period that I&amp;rsquo;ve finally got sorted and fixed to my bike.
Brooks Saddle The first part I got hold of was a new saddle. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t after one, but this came up for a price that was entirely reasonable so I decided to snap it up.

I&amp;rsquo;d been considering getting a Brooks Cambium saddle for the Verenti for a while - it was either that or a Charge Spoon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Ride - A few photos and a puncture!</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2017/02/sunday-ride-a-few-photos-and-a-puncture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 07:47:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2017/02/sunday-ride-a-few-photos-and-a-puncture/</guid>
      <description>I managed to get out this morning for a short ride on my cyclocross bike - it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve ridden it as I&amp;rsquo;m using my Dawes touring bike for commuting and I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the chance to get out at the weekend for a while due to cadet activities.
So whilst the weather was good this morning, I managed to get out and about before the rain that was forecast for the afternoon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eddington Number</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2017/01/eddington-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 15:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2017/01/eddington-number/</guid>
      <description>Eddington Number I&amp;rsquo;m a keen user of Veloviewer as it provides some excellent methods of viewing my Strava data in a way that Strava can or does not provide, whilst adding on additional statistics.
I like it enough that I pay for the premium version (£10 a year) and I feel tha this is money well spent. Whilst I&amp;rsquo;ve said before that cycling isn&amp;rsquo;t all about the numbers, I do find myself as an engineer enjoying looking at the figures as well!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pi-Hole</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2017/01/pi-hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 19:21:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2017/01/pi-hole/</guid>
      <description>Pi Hole I had my Raspberry Pi lying around doing nothing. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a version 1 since they were released and I&amp;rsquo;ve had a version 2 for a while as well (in fact, I&amp;rsquo;ve been through two version 2&amp;rsquo;s). I&amp;rsquo;ve had this one in the draw for a while now doing nothing - it&amp;rsquo;s not really seen the light of day since I purchased my Synology DS116 as I had been using it as a home server and accessing my documents via SFTP outside the house.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annual Summary 2016</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/12/annual-summary-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 19:35:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/12/annual-summary-2016/</guid>
      <description>Yearly Summary This year has been a roller-coaster year to be honest, full of ups and downs.
January started with a new job on the outskirts of London - potentially meaning that I could get out on my bike a lot more cycling to work. However, I seem to have spent the majority of the time on my bike commuting to and from work and the social rides and just rides at the weekend have been missing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proviz Backpack Review</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/12/proviz-backpack-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 16:36:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/12/proviz-backpack-review/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that winter is slowly but surely coming - it&amp;rsquo;s getting darker both in the morning cycling to work and in the evening cycling home.
However, it&amp;rsquo;s not yet cold enough that I can wear my Proviz jacket - not the Nightrider I reviewed back in 2014, but the REFLECT360+ that I purchased in 2015. The newer jacket still suffers from some of the same issues as the original one that I tried - I overheat very quickly within the Proviz jackets it seems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polar M400 Review</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/11/polar-m400-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 15:57:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/11/polar-m400-review/</guid>
      <description>I bought the Polar M400 sports watch not long after getting my Polar V650. I&amp;rsquo;d decided that the Polar ecosystem was quite good, and was something that I might want to focus on a bit more. The training features of the Polar Flow site seemed to be good. However, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to import data from other services, such as Garmin and even work arounds wouldn&amp;rsquo;t allow me to upload my own data to the service and make use of the training load graph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Domain Name Provider</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/10/new-domain-name-provider/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 18:51:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/10/new-domain-name-provider/</guid>
      <description>This month, one of my domains was up for renewal. Currently I own four domains and they&amp;rsquo;ve all been with 123-Reg for many years. However, the service I&amp;rsquo;ve had from them and the communication in response to a query was pretty poor - I realised that I&amp;rsquo;d had to contact them the year before regarding a renewal as well! So all in all, I decided to take my business elsewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Bike</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/10/new-bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/10/new-bike/</guid>
      <description>This weekend finally saw me get the chance to ride my new bike.
I&amp;rsquo;d made use of the Cycle to Work offer that my firm offer through Cyclescheme. The offer allows me to save money on the purchase of a new bike through tax savings - I&amp;rsquo;ve never really been hugely convinced that the deal saves me money (though I&amp;rsquo;m assured that it does), but it is a method of getting a new bike with interest free credit for 12 months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polar V650</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/09/polar-v650/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 10:41:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/09/polar-v650/</guid>
      <description>The past few months have seen me try to increase my running at the expense of my cycling. Comparing my overall mileage for the year, I&amp;rsquo;m probably on the lowest distance to date since 2011. However, the running has improved and I&amp;rsquo;m hitting personal bests that I set whilst I was running during university. I have tried to maintain the cycling at least once a week though, cycling to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trigo Mount In Use</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/06/trigo-mount-in-use-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 18:45:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/06/trigo-mount-in-use-2/</guid>
      <description>So I managed to use the Trigo Garmin bike mount I wrote about the other day on my way to work.
I have to say that whilst it performed the job reasonably well, I had a few issues with it.
Firstly, when the Trigo is attached so that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fold into my wheels when the Brompton folds down, the display isn&amp;rsquo;t in the best location on the handlebars. I can&amp;rsquo;t adjust this without an Allen Key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gigabyte Brix BXBT 2807</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/06/gigabyte-brix-bxbt-2807-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 18:40:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/06/gigabyte-brix-bxbt-2807-2/</guid>
      <description>I was trying to install Windows 10 on the recently purchased Gigabyte BRIX-BXBT-2807 that I got the other day and I was struggling.
It would boot the Windows 10 USB up without any issues and would then allow me to go off and install it. Windows copies the files to the disk and then reboots as any normal install.
On boot, it would then however sit there at the boot screen and wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even boot into Windows to continue the install.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trigo Garmin Mount</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/06/trigo-garmin-mount-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 18:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/06/trigo-garmin-mount-2/</guid>
      <description>Last week I found out about a Garmin mount from Taiwan called the Trigo. This mounts to the stem of the Brompton where the handlebars meet.
This overcomes one of my issues with my current setup for the Brompton in that my GPS starts rotating around the handlebars occasionally and it has also caused some surface marks to the handlebar. Putting the Garmin onto the handlebars also means that I have to rotate the Garmin mount so I can attach the Garmin anyhow as the top of the stem gets in the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zim Journalling</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/05/zim-journalling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 15:31:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/05/zim-journalling/</guid>
      <description>Zim and Journalling I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Day One for probably close to five years. In that time, I&amp;rsquo;ve built up quite a database of journal entries.
However, with the release of version 2 of Day One, they have moved to running their own sync service - which I can understand and I can see the benefits of, as it allows them to add in additional features to the software that using iCloud or Dropbox sync wouldn&amp;rsquo;t let them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Bike</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/04/one-bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 14:08:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/04/one-bike/</guid>
      <description>One Bike Cycling to work today on my touring bike, it occurred to me that whilst I have three bikes, I would probably be happy with just the one.
This was in my mind because yesterday I was thinking that when the time comes around for the Cycle to Work vouchers at work to be issued, I could consider getting myself a Pashley Sovereign to commute to work on (that&amp;rsquo;s besides the fact that I commute to work on my Dawes currently!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Footpath App</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/03/footpath-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 11:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/03/footpath-app/</guid>
      <description>The iPad is a great device - sitting on the sofa, on the train or just where ever, the iPad (Mini in my case) is a fantastic tool. I can happily write a blog post, browse the Internet or generally do pretty much anything I can do on the Mac on the go using the iPad.
One exception has been to plan my biking or running routes. For this, I&amp;rsquo;ve used Ride with GPS on the Mac to create my routes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Bell</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/03/new-bell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 21:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/03/new-bell/</guid>
      <description>I picked up a new toy for my bike this past week. My Dawes bike hasn&amp;rsquo;t had a bell on it, probably since I bought the bike. It came with one, but it&amp;rsquo;s pretty poor bell that the bike came with (something cheap and nasty that the bike has to be sold with in the UK). It just about works. Nothing special.
Anyhow, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the bike for a while now but I&amp;rsquo;ve not had a bell on it and this can get annoying - riding to work, the majority of the route is along a shared path and it means that I can&amp;rsquo;t warn people that I&amp;rsquo;m coming up behind them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LBC London to Gravesend</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/02/lbc-london-to-gravesend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 20:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/02/lbc-london-to-gravesend/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a month since I attended a London Brompton Club ride, so I&amp;rsquo;d been looking forward to the one on the 20th Feb - London to Gravesend. It would take the Pilgrims Way for some of the route and having done this as part of the Whitstable ride last year, I was looking forward to it as I recalled that the scenery (once out of South London) was fantastic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road Traffic Collision</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/02/road-traffic-collision/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 20:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/02/road-traffic-collision/</guid>
      <description>Heading to work on Monday morning, I had my first Road Traffic Collision (RTC). It&amp;rsquo;s not really an experience I want to go through again!
I&amp;rsquo;d left for work just before 7am as I normally do when I&amp;rsquo;m riding - this gives me plenty of time to get to work and then grab a shower before I start. I&amp;rsquo;d taken the Brompton as it had been a while since I&amp;rsquo;d ridden it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye Dropbox!</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/02/goodbye-dropbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 10:10:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/02/goodbye-dropbox/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve done something this week that I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve done for almost five years - I&amp;rsquo;ve removed Dropbox from my Mac.
gasp
I know, how could I?
Well, I think it&amp;rsquo;s slowly been a long time coming. Since I bought my Synology1, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using that more and more for various items. Up until recently however, it hadn&amp;rsquo;t come close enough to replacing Dropbox fully. However, I think the time now has come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plain Text Blogging</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/02/plain-text-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 10:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/02/plain-text-blogging/</guid>
      <description>For the past two years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing my blog in Markdown and plain text - in fact, almost everything I write at home is in plain text format - using nValt, Byword and Marked2 I&amp;rsquo;m able to write everything I need (blog posts, emails and magazine articles) 1 2. With these three apps, I&amp;rsquo;ve been happily able to work on my MacBook, Windows laptop, work laptop, iPad, Amazon Fire tablet, Android phone and iPhone 3 - plain text documents synced to the cloud via Dropbox and accessible anywhere from pretty much any device I happen to be using.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strava Route Change</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/02/strava-route-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 18:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/02/strava-route-change/</guid>
      <description>Looking at one of my PR&amp;rsquo;s on Strava today in regards to my ride in at the start of the week and I noticed some odd sections. It seems that Strava was pushing me down roads that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t actually been down.
![Strava app, showing my route not on the cycle path](http://vox.me.uk/images/2016-02-02 16.07.25.png)
I first thought that this was my GPS being silly and placing me in the wrong location. However, I compared the same GPS track in Ride With GPS as it is in Strava.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garmin Vivoactive Continued</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/01/garmin-vivoactive-continued/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 21:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2016/01/garmin-vivoactive-continued/</guid>
      <description>So another article on the Garmin Vivoactive!
As you know, I&amp;rsquo;ve done a few other articles on the Garmin Vivoactive (here and here). However, I can add a bit more to the continued &amp;ldquo;series&amp;rdquo; now! I&amp;rsquo;ve tested the device on Android (a Wileyfox Swift, a British mobile phone brand) and can now compare this to iOS, which I had been running it on.
The Wileyfox is running Cyanogen OS, so results might be slightly different on other Android phones with different brands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garmin Vivoactive</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/09/garming-vivoactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 23:42:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/09/garming-vivoactive/</guid>
      <description>Background I never used to be a watch person, though that all change when I started running when at Loughborough and then when I moved to London and was at the mercy of trains (and meetings), I found a watch to be something I couldn&amp;rsquo;t leave behind.
For years, I used a classic - the Casio F-91W.
Not only was it bombproof (though, perhaps the wrong word to use there considering that owning one of the watches in Afghanistan was apparently enough to cause the Americans to detain you for questioning as it was often the watch used for detonators!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LBC: London to Brighton Again</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/07/lbc-london-to-brighton-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 20:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/07/lbc-london-to-brighton-again/</guid>
      <description>This weekend I headed down to Brighton with some of the London Brompton Club.
I&amp;rsquo;d offered this ride to some of my work colleagues as we did this ride last year and it was a great ride, thanks to David&amp;rsquo;s excellent navigating skills, and a couple decided to come along this weekend. I also offered it to the LBC as well, though I was aware that this would clash with the Dunwhich Dynamo that was being ridden that evening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phone GPS</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/07/phone-gps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 20:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/07/phone-gps/</guid>
      <description>On the London to Whitstable ride, I made use of my Samsung S5. This let me make use of the apps on my phone, rather than my old Garmin unit for showing directions.
I sold my Garmin recently - this was partly down to the fact that I could use the Samsung for navigating and partly because I never seem to have the Garmin with me, but my phone goes everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Month of Cycling</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/07/month-of-cycling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 23:42:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/07/month-of-cycling/</guid>
      <description>So July is upon us already and with it some of the hottest days of the year, with temperatures reaching 36°C in places!
Anyhow, taking the idea from earlier in the year from the 30 Days of Biking challenge, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that July that I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to and ride every day for the month. That means a tracked ride in Strava and not just the commute to work. I didn&amp;rsquo;t do it in April as I was away for business part of the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mosquito Ride Preparation</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/06/mosquito-ride-preperation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 20:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/06/mosquito-ride-preperation/</guid>
      <description>Today I decided to ride part of the route I&amp;rsquo;ve got planned for the LBC ride on July 25th. I&amp;rsquo;ve ridden the first section numerous times - St Albans, Hatfield and Potters Bar featured heavily on my rides over the past few years as I lived there. However, I&amp;rsquo;d never really ventured past Hertford and so the second half of the route was a complete blank to me. Not really ideal for leading a ride over in that direction!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LBC: Tweed Ride</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/05/lbc-tweed-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 14:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/05/lbc-tweed-ride/</guid>
      <description>This weekend saw the Brompton club do a tweed themed ride to celebrate a couple of members 40th birthdays (though, neither of them eventually made the ride, unfortunately). I&amp;rsquo;m not sure where the tweed part came in but it was an amusing addition to the ride!
I&amp;rsquo;ve a tweed jacket, but I ended up wearing a retro merino wool jersey that I&amp;rsquo;d got from Stolen Goat. Tweed is ok, but as we edge towards summer, I think I&amp;rsquo;d have been far far to warm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LBC: London to Whitstable</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/05/lbc-london-to-whitstable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 11:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/05/lbc-london-to-whitstable/</guid>
      <description>Saturday morning is usually my lie in - its not often that my alarm will get me up at 6am in the morning on a Saturday as well as the work week! However, this weekend was different as I left Wimbledon on a train at 06:21 to get to Trafalgar Square. Why would I get up so early? Because of a bike ride!
The LBC have run a ride to Whitstable now for the last three years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work iPhone</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/05/work-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 11:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/05/work-iphone/</guid>
      <description>So work recently bought me an iPhone as my work phone. Whilst I&amp;rsquo;m happy with this (as much as I like Android, I find iOS to be better), it has led to a few head scratching moments.
Namely, as an Apple user for a fair amount of time, I&amp;rsquo;ve purchased a fair amount of apps on the App Store that I want to use on the work phone, but I&amp;rsquo;m hampered by the fact it&amp;rsquo;s linked to a new AppleID, one created with my work email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tannus Tyres</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/05/tannus-tyres/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 15:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/05/tannus-tyres/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, I upgraded my Brompton to the puncture proof, Tannus tyres. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a puncture twice now on my Bromptons - both times occurring when I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a puncture repair kit with me (once, as I was on a quick ride around Hatfield and the other when I was commuting home from work) so I&amp;rsquo;ve been forced to walk the bike home in both instances (in fairness, I tried to get a bus home with the Brompton the last time, but the local bus service in Welwyn threw that idea out the window - the time waiting for the next bus, I&amp;rsquo;d have actually got home).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LBC: Kew and Cake</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/05/lbc-kew-and-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 17:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/05/lbc-kew-and-cake/</guid>
      <description>Saturday saw me do a ride with the London Brompton club. It&amp;rsquo;s the first ride I&amp;rsquo;ve done with them for quite a while to be fair due to various reasons (such as not being in the country!)
The promise of cake made the ride seem like a good prospect and the good weather we&amp;rsquo;d been having for the last few days made me think that perhaps the ride would be accompanied with good weather.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ireland Bike Ride</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/04/ireland-bike-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 20:10:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/04/ireland-bike-ride/</guid>
      <description>I have recently spent a few days in Ireland for a holiday, meeting my girlfriends family and friends from back home. Whilst I was there, I managed to get out and about for a quick bike ride.
I borrowed a bike from one of the family members and did a loop of the local area whilst the house was being setup for the extended family to arrive over the weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Battle of Britain Challenge</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/04/battle-of-britain-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 19:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/04/battle-of-britain-challenge/</guid>
      <description>To date this year, I&amp;rsquo;ve not really signed up to do any bike challenges. About this time last year, I&amp;rsquo;d cycled from London to Loughborough, but I currently haven&amp;rsquo;t planned anything similar this year. I&amp;rsquo;d talked about doing the Devon Coast to Coast or the Way of the Roses but this has been hot air for the time being. I thought it was about time that I signed up and did something this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling in Berlin</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/04/cycling-in-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 19:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/04/cycling-in-berlin/</guid>
      <description>I spent last weekend in Berlin, as part of a work trip to Germany for a conference. Whilst I was there, I decided to spend some time cycling around Berlin with Fat Tire Bike Tours.
I&amp;rsquo;d spent a few days walking around Magdeburg whilst I was there, mainly from the university (where the conference was) to the hotel, making sure I got to see the sights along the way. I&amp;rsquo;d considered taking the Brompton with me, as my flight tickets included a checked bag, but I decided not to this time around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ortlieb Bags</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/03/ortlieb-bags/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 20:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/03/ortlieb-bags/</guid>
      <description>Since my Patagonia bag failed catastrophically at protecting the contents of my bag from water in January, I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at preventing it happening again. Things such as keeping electronics from the upper pocket that was affected by the rain water was the start. I then went on to buy a HUMP rain proof cover but found that the size supposed to fit my bag size was to small and didn&amp;rsquo;t offer decent protection - it often kept slipping off the top and exposing the zip that was caused the initial problem!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Bike</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/03/so-i-bought-a-new-bike-today-the-n-1-rule-is-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 21:50:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/03/so-i-bought-a-new-bike-today-the-n-1-rule-is-a/</guid>
      <description>So I bought a new bike today. The n + 1 rule is a commonly known belief amongst cyclists in that the best number of bikes to own is the current number (n) plus one. Whilst this rule applies, I’ve not actually purchased this bike for myself!
I think I’ve slowly worn my girlfriend down and there’s been talk of us riding together.
Well, I bought a new helmet for myself at the London Bike Show and she’d said she wasn’t going to go riding without a helmet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vulpine Purchases</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/02/vulpine-purchases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 21:34:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/02/vulpine-purchases/</guid>
      <description>I was lucky enough last week to get a chance to visit the Vulpine sample sale. Vulpine are a British gear manufacturer that make stylish clothes that appear to rival Rapha in quality. When it was posted on the London Brompton Club Facebook page, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d get myself over there for a look.
Vulpine I didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to get there until the evening. I got there about 17:00, having left work slightly early to see what was left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weeks Riding</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/01/weeks-riding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 20:55:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/01/weeks-riding/</guid>
      <description>This past week has seen me ride more than I rode in the entirety of last January! In fact, taking into account the Evans organised ride, it means that I&amp;rsquo;ve done about three times the amount of cycling in comparison to last year!
I&amp;rsquo;ve put in 19 hours to date this month, and this time last year, I&amp;rsquo;d completed 10 (and that included runs, which I&amp;rsquo;ve not done this year). In terms of distance, that&amp;rsquo;s a bit more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evans Ride It! - Osterley</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/01/evans-ride-it-osterley/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 18:20:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/01/evans-ride-it-osterley/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday, I took part in my first Evans Ride It sportive - I&amp;rsquo;d booked one of these to ride in 2013 (the Hatfield one) but due to illness, I didn&amp;rsquo;t get a chance to ride it. So when I saw this one advertised before Christmas, I decided that I&amp;rsquo;d give it a go. I signed up for the long distance but saw that I could drop down to the medium on the day if I wanted which could be good if bad weather came in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Purchases and Ride</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/01/new-purchases-and-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 19:18:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/01/new-purchases-and-ride/</guid>
      <description>With the Christmas sales on, I decided to get myself a few new items for the bike. I&amp;rsquo;ve put them through their paces today on my ride home from Wimbledon.
Castelli Gloves My gloves of choice, my Rab power stretch grip gloves were getting a bit chilly in the very cold weather that had come in recently. Most importantly, they were letting the win chill in and was causing some uncomfortable early morning cycles to the office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year in Review</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/12/year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 13:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/12/year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>So this is my first year in review for my blog - so it has been &amp;ldquo;A Year in Bike&amp;rdquo; and that&amp;rsquo;ll continue on into 2015. It&amp;rsquo;s been a good year, so here&amp;rsquo;s a quick year in review post.
Highlights Highlights this year were:
  Getting the Brompton.
  Taking part in the London Brompton Club rides.
  My bike &amp;ldquo;tour&amp;rdquo; from Loughborough to London.
  The St Crispins Ride overnight ride (this years only century).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Size Bikes</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/12/full-size-bikes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 13:35:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/12/full-size-bikes/</guid>
      <description>So now I&amp;rsquo;ve settled down and moved into my flat and tidied up a bit, I&amp;rsquo;ve got my full size bike back.
I spent today getting it roadworthy again so I can take it out this week whilst I&amp;rsquo;m off work. It&amp;rsquo;s been in storage for the past nine months and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t really used much before it went into storage so this mainly consisted of getting the saddle sorted again and sorting out the brakes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Image Sharing and Embedding</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/12/personal-image-sharing-and-embedding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/12/personal-image-sharing-and-embedding/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at writing more of my blog posts on my iPad. However, up until I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been using Flickr for storing all my images and displaying them on my site. This has worked well in the past but has been a long winded - on the iMac, the image is copied into iPhoto and then uploaded to Flickr via that. Adding the image to the blog post is achieved by inserting the image using MarsEdit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veloviewer Review</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/12/veloviewer-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2014 15:10:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/12/veloviewer-review/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a keen Strava user and have been for some time. I upgraded to Strava Pro last year in preparation for my training for the London Bikeathon but let it lapse after I finished that ride - I couldn&amp;rsquo;t quite justify the cost of it without a training aim.
However, I found that occasionally I still wanted to access stats that where inaccessible or not shown on Strava and that&amp;rsquo;s when I discovered Veloviewer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Headers</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/12/markdown-headers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2014 14:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/12/markdown-headers/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing a lot more in Markdown. Markdown is simple and easy to use, as I&amp;rsquo;ve pointed out before.
Whilst nValt offers a good search function to find data within a note, I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring additional details that I could add to files to make them easier to find. Well, it turns out that MultiMarkdown supports meta data or headers, something I didn&amp;rsquo;t realise even though I use MMD more than vanilla Markdown more often than not!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Purchases</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/12/recent-purchases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2014 10:12:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/12/recent-purchases/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve made some new purchases for the Brompton. Nothing to fancy or special but upgrades I believed were now required.
Cleats I&amp;rsquo;d held off on getting cleats for the Brompton for about a year now - however, the wet weather of the winter was making me think that that they were a good idea. In the recent weather, my feet have been slipping all over the pedals - I hadn&amp;rsquo;t quite yet managed to have my feet come off, but it had been close.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPad Update</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/12/ipad-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 20:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/12/ipad-update/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been using a tablet since I got my iPad 2 for a Christmas a few years back. I eventually upgraded that to an iPad Mini which I’ve then had for almost the past two years.
I’ve briefly experimented with an Android tablet (the Tesco Hudl and Hudl 2) but I haven’t been impressed with them. I just don’t get on with Android it seems.
However, I’d been debating if I wanted to upgrade the iPad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidying Markdown Tables</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/11/tidying-markdown-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2014 11:07:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/11/tidying-markdown-tables/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d been a fan of Dr Drang&amp;rsquo;s table tidy script for Markdown, especially the one he&amp;rsquo;s recently updated here.
However, he&amp;rsquo;s a BBEdit user and I don&amp;rsquo;t use BBEdit. I&amp;rsquo;m a fairly basic user, and I&amp;rsquo;ll stick with Textastic, nValt and Byword for my writing (LaTeX and Markdown respectively), so I didn&amp;rsquo;t think I could use his code.
Turns out I&amp;rsquo;m wrong.
The Script Dr Drang seems to write most of his scripts in Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carradice Trial</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/11/carradice-trial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 21:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/11/carradice-trial/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been having to take more and more stuff into the office with me. I change in the office every morning and work have recently given me a laptop. As such, I&amp;rsquo;ve found that I&amp;rsquo;ve outgrown the Brompton S bag - come weekends when I&amp;rsquo;m staying away, I have to resort to using a backpack. Likewise, any day I fancy swimming, I have to take an additional bag.
After lamenting on the London Brompton Club Facebook page, it was suggested I try a saddlebag as I can&amp;rsquo;t really use the T or M bag on the Brompton and even the full size O bag isn&amp;rsquo;t recommended for the S type handlebars (though I have in the past managed to fit the T type onto my S type handlebars which was interesting trying to brake and steer!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brompton Sale</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/11/brompton-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 20:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/11/brompton-sale/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I decided with some regret, that one of my Brompton&amp;rsquo;s would have to be sold.
The P type had been used for some long rides - it was the reason I was able to get my first taste of bike touring (Loughborogh to London) earlier this year.
However, I&amp;rsquo;ve only ridden it a few times since then - even the 100 mile ride I did with the Brompton Club for the St Crispins Day night ride was done on my S type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camelbak Review</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/11/camelbak-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 11:27:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/11/camelbak-review/</guid>
      <description>After buying my Brompton and using it on few rides with the London Brompton Club, I came to the conclusion that for the longer rides, I would need to get myself something to drink from - I&amp;rsquo;d already got myself a white O bag to match the Brompton, thanks to one of the Brompton owners selling one. However, whilst the bag is handy for carrying my tool kit and inner tubes, it&amp;rsquo;s not that helpful for holding a drink for easy access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambridge Ride</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/10/cambridge-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 20:17:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/10/cambridge-ride/</guid>
      <description>(This is a very delayed post from September that I forgot to press send to blog on! A number of photos are used with permission.)
Saturday saw me take on the role of ride leader for the first time in the LBC group with a ride I&amp;rsquo;d planned from Hatfield to Cambridge. I&amp;rsquo;ve ridden this route in the past before, so I knew what to expect.
I&amp;rsquo;d originally planned to do this ride in August but postponed it until September.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promise Nightrider Jacket Review</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/10/promise-nightrider-jacket-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 19:14:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/10/promise-nightrider-jacket-review/</guid>
      <description>Last month, I picked up a Proviz Nightrider cycling jacket after reading the review by Orange Brompton. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a few words on it, now that I&amp;rsquo;ve had it for a while.
In Short In short, it&amp;rsquo;s good, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;d go as far as Orange and say it&amp;rsquo;s the best cycling jacket ever.
It&amp;rsquo;s a very good jacket, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are some on the market that are better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teva Shoes</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/09/teva-shoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 19:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/09/teva-shoes/</guid>
      <description>Shoes don&amp;rsquo;t seem like an interesting blog post - however, I sometimes think I&amp;rsquo;m guilty of being the wrong sex, as I seem to have a few shopping habits that the fairer sex are often stereotypically attributed with - that is, I have a thing for good bags. However, shoes (the other vice women are usually labelled with!) are not something I usually get excited about.
However, this is potentially due to the fact that I could never find a good pair - I would settle for a cheap £20 pair of Airwalk&amp;rsquo;s from Sports Direct as I seem to destroy shoes (the soles would wear through within a month or two).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loki&#39;s First Service</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/09/lokis-first-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 09:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/09/lokis-first-service/</guid>
      <description>So it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve written here, but things have changed a bit since I&amp;rsquo;ve been away. For a start, I&amp;rsquo;ve moved - things finally worked out and my house purchase went through!
That means that for a while, I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting sorted in my new flat with everything that comes with buying your own house. On the plus side, I have a nice new location for the Bromptons!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logging Phone Calls with Day One</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/09/logging-phone-calls-with-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 20:16:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/09/logging-phone-calls-with-day-one/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve covered before my use of Launch Centre Pro (LCP) to easily create a book log in Day One, by using the URL links within iOS and setting up the same in Keyboard Maestro so I can make life easier wherever I am.
However, I&amp;rsquo;ve recently created another action that I felt was worth sharing - one for logging telephone calls.
Logging Calls Normally, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t log my calls, however, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to make a number of calls to companies for whatever reason - today, it&amp;rsquo;s been because money hasn&amp;rsquo;t been taken from my account for insurance and I wanted to see what the issue was - and more importantly, ensure that there were no fees to pay and that my policy was still in place (it happens that as it was there mistake, my policy is fine).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Plain Text</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/08/working-with-plain-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 10:58:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/08/working-with-plain-text/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve spoken before on my use of LaTeX for my thesis. This allowed me to create a great looking thesis, with easy linking, cross referencing and bibliography that users of Microsoft Word struggle with!
As plain text, this allowed me to edit my files on the Mac, Windows and iPad with ease - in fact, I write about my attempts to use the iPad only here, which includes me editing my thesis on the go on the iPad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ride London</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/08/ride-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 19:34:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/08/ride-london/</guid>
      <description>So this weekend has been the Ride London cycling festival.
For those that don&amp;rsquo;t know, the Ride London festival is a two day cycling festival with the Saturday seeing many of London&amp;rsquo;s roads closed to allow people to cycle traffic free along parts of London that would usually be full of cars. The Sunday sees the traffic free roads extend down into Dorking and Surrey to allow riders to cycle a 100 mile route with no traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London to Brighton</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/07/london-to-brighton/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 19:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/07/london-to-brighton/</guid>
      <description>I finally managed to get the second long ride I&amp;rsquo;d been meaning to do since moving to London done this weekend - London to Brighton.
The Brompton club planned and rode this ride a few weeks ago, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to make it, due to a last minute change of plans and trip to Dorset instead. However, a group of work colleagues wanted to do a London to Brighton ride, so using the course that the Brompton guys had already ridden, I volunteered as ride leader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hatfield to Cambridge - Again</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/07/hatfield-to-cambirdge-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 08:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/07/hatfield-to-cambirdge-again/</guid>
      <description>So today I ended up doing another Cambridge ride - I&amp;rsquo;ve pencilled this route in for a London Brompton Club ride in September so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give it another run through to ensure that I know where I&amp;rsquo;m going and to make sure the route is fine.
No pictures from the ride - I think I&amp;rsquo;m becoming guilty of jumping on the bike and just going again, it seems like I need to do a few more social rides to exorcise that from the system!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch Center Pro and Day One</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/07/launch-center-pro-and-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2014 09:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/07/launch-center-pro-and-day-one/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently discovered Launch Center Pro for iOS that lets you create actions and generally extends the abilities of iOS a bit (basically allowing you to create shortcuts to tasks you do often).
There&amp;rsquo;s a number of things I do on the iPhone or iPad consistently, so being able to do these from a single app can make it shorter to do. It&amp;rsquo;s a one stop shop for accessing stuff. For example, I&amp;rsquo;ve set up a shortcut so I can message both my mum and dad at the same time, without having to open Messages, select new message (or find a previous message I&amp;rsquo;ve sent to them both) and add them both to the message and then compose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Cloud Reliance</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/07/breaking-cloud-reliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2014 08:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/07/breaking-cloud-reliance/</guid>
      <description>Everything seems to use the cloud today and whilst I was initially happy worth that, things such as PRISM and the Snowden releases have left me feeling a bit more lost at sea perhaps. I love the cloud, it makes accessing my own files etc a lot easier, but I also want to be in more control of my data. I also don&amp;rsquo;t want to end up paying for drive space if I can help it and I seem to be increasing my file usages fairly considerably.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tour De France</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/07/tour-de-france/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 10:39:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/07/tour-de-france/</guid>
      <description>So, unless it escaped your notice, the Tour De France recently started the 2014 tour with three stages in the UK to mark the Grand Depart of the 101st race.
The first two stages were held in Yorkshire (Leeds to Harrogate and then York to Sheffield). The third, Cambridge to London, was a bit closer to home and I thought this was finally my chance to view the famous race in person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YNAB from Moneywiz!</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/06/ynab-from-moneywiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 08:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/06/ynab-from-moneywiz/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been almost a year since I switched from using Moneywiz! to YNAB. YNAB (or You Need A Budget), is a money tracking software suite that works on Windows, Mac and has Android and iOS apps.
Moneywiz was a decent piece of software. During uni, I was using GNUCash to keep track of my spending and it performed reasonably well. However, it was dog slow when I moved to the Mac and it was ugly as sin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekend Away</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/06/weekend-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 20:33:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/06/weekend-away/</guid>
      <description>This weekend I had initially planned to go on a ride with the London Brompton Club to Hove (starting at Richmond). However, a text from my parents meant that I ended up changing my plans, and headed out instead to Dorset for the weekend.
Complete change of plans and I something I hadn&amp;rsquo;t planned for at all (I got the text at 15:00 on Friday afternoon, so I bought my train tickets online and headed to Waterloo at 17:00 when I finished!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday Evening Ride</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/06/wednesday-evening-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2014 21:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/06/wednesday-evening-ride/</guid>
      <description>Wednesday evenings are usually spent at home, not doing much at all. Though I am trying to learn German, it&amp;rsquo;s not going well and so any excuse to get out the house and away from any such talk of football due to the world cup is good (or learning how to complain that my food tastes salty auf Deutsch…) is a good reason to get out and about.
Following on from a previous ride by Brompton themselves, David from the LBC kindly organised a brief jaunt for Wednesday night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhoto</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/06/iphoto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2014 13:06:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/06/iphoto/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using a Mac now for a fair few years. Probably approaching five years if I sit and think about. It all started when I bought my Mac Mini during my PhD. Well, that was a great purchase and since then I&amp;rsquo;ve moved on from the Mac Mini to a 27&amp;quot; iMac and a MacBook Air.
Anyhow, since I started with the Mac, there were a few things that I&amp;rsquo;ve not used on them - one of which was iPhoto.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dressing Up</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/06/dressing-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2014 19:24:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/06/dressing-up/</guid>
      <description>So a while ago, Loki got a new saddle. However, the other item I&amp;rsquo;d been toying with getting for the Brompton since getting it, was a set of grips.
Of course, these would have to be Ergon grips, as since trying them on my other bike, I&amp;rsquo;ve been sorely impressed with them (well, no soreness at all, as that&amp;rsquo;s part of the reason for buying them!) For longer journeys, they all for different riding positions (with the bar ends) and are more comfortable than the standard Brompton grips for day to day to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brompton Junction Ride</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/06/brompton-junction-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2014 11:40:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/06/brompton-junction-ride/</guid>
      <description>So this evening we there was a ride organised by Brompton Junction.
I only saw the email yesterday but thought I&amp;rsquo;d register, after all, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t doing anything else this evening.
I got there slightly early so I could have a cup of tea and a slice of the treacle tart. I must admit the tart and tea there are some of the best I&amp;rsquo;ve had in London so it&amp;rsquo;s always worth a trip, solely for the food and drink!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London Bike Ride</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/06/london-bike-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 19:54:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/06/london-bike-ride/</guid>
      <description>I reaslised that although I&amp;rsquo;ve been in London now for about two years (I was offered my job on 12th June 2012 and then started on the 9th July…), I perhaps hadn&amp;rsquo;t done as much exploring as I could have done.
This was backed up by the Brompton Urban Challenge where I got to ride some more roads that I might not have travelled. Likewise, just going on London Brompton club rides has shown me a lot more of London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brooks Saddle</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/05/brooks-saddle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 18:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/05/brooks-saddle/</guid>
      <description>When I bought the Brompton, there was the option of upgrading the saddle to a Brooks saddle. I decided against on the basis that I would see how the standard Brompton saddle faired as the one on the test model I&amp;rsquo;d ridden didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to bad. I&amp;rsquo;m also not a fan of the Brooks saddle - I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the look.
So I stuck with the Brompton saddle for a few hundred miles and it didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to bad at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London Brompton Urban Challenge 2014</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/05/london-brompton-urban-challenge-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 08:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/05/london-brompton-urban-challenge-2014/</guid>
      <description>This past Sunday saw me take part in the Brompton Urban Challenge. This can be best described as a Brompton treasure hunt around London, riding around, following the clues give at each checkpoint to get to the next checkpoint whilst carrying out challenges along the way. I&amp;rsquo;d done a similar type of ride during my time at Loughborough University where I&amp;rsquo;d taken part in a mountain biking treasure hunt and managed to come third (much to the disgust of the organiser, my housemate, due to the fact I cycled a hybrid and mainly cycled between the parts on the road!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London Space for Cycling</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/05/london-space-for-cycling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2014 19:10:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/05/london-space-for-cycling/</guid>
      <description>Well, a bright sunny day in London today and it marked the London Cycling Campaign&amp;rsquo;s Big Ride. This ride is a, I guess, a protest ride drawing attention to the fact that London cyclists would like more room for cycling.
Whilst I don&amp;rsquo;t agree with all that the LCC want (some of it is beyond what could sensibly be done, other than shutting traffic out of London completely), but I still think it&amp;rsquo;s important to support them (CTC of which I am a member is also supporting the Space for Cycling campaign as well, as it&amp;rsquo;s now a nationwide movement) as I would love to see some well thought out changes to cycling in London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hatfield to Cambridge</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/05/hatfield-to-cambridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 14:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/05/hatfield-to-cambridge/</guid>
      <description>So Monday was a Bank Holiday in the UK which meant I was off work. I wanted to do a ride but wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what to do as I wanted something reasonably long.
Turns out you can plan a ride within 30 minutes on RideWithGPS and set off and go!
I&amp;rsquo;d been wanting to do a London to Cambridge route for a while now - don&amp;rsquo;t ask me why, but it seems to be one of those rides you have to do if you live in London (the other being London to Brighton).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SFTP &#43; Dropbox</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/04/sftp-dropbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 18:54:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/04/sftp-dropbox/</guid>
      <description>Dropbox is a fantastic service for syncing documents. In fact, some form of digital syncing is now pretty much built into my workflow that I struggle to use an electronic device with out it! It allows me to keep my eBooks up to date (thanks to Calibre), allows me to sync my Zotero library of academic papers and generally keep my laptop and desktop in sync.
However, whilst Dropbox works amazingly at home, perhaps understandably there are times where it&amp;rsquo;s blocked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting the Sunday Ride Short</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/04/cutting-the-sunday-ride-short/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 18:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/04/cutting-the-sunday-ride-short/</guid>
      <description>So today I ended up going for a ride and aborted it early.
Partly due to the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m still a bit saddle sore from last weekend - the Brompton turns out is pretty decent (I&amp;rsquo;ve used it for about 60Km a ride before, see the data for the London Classic and the LBC ride, the Thames Triple Chaser). These rides were fine and the saddle performed fine. However, over the distance I rode last weekend and the partly gravelly nature of the route (I think), the saddle did end up causing some chafing and discomfort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekend Touring</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/04/weekend-touring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 19:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/04/weekend-touring/</guid>
      <description>Well, this weekend I managed to get a ride in that I&amp;rsquo;d had in my mind for a while since I&amp;rsquo;d considered doing bike touring - that is a ride from Loughborough to London.
It all came about one day one of my friends jokingly suggested that I should cycle to one of the LAN&amp;rsquo;s I go to with the Loughborough Computer Societyy. Well this got me thinking and I thought I&amp;rsquo;d have a good look at what would be entailed to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Brompton Family Grows</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/04/the-brompton-family-grows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 19:25:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/04/the-brompton-family-grows/</guid>
      <description>So it&amp;rsquo;s not been long since I&amp;rsquo;ve had my Brompton - it arrived in February.
However, I&amp;rsquo;ve already managed to add another one to my collection!
We Love Bromptons! had a 2012 Blue P6R model up for sale recently at a decent price so I ended up getting it. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t my initial plan to do so - I had been planning on touring on my hybrid this year but then when my house deal fell through, I had to move into rented accommodation quickly and wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to get anywhere where I could store a full size bike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thames Triple Chaser</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/03/thames-triple-chaser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 15:04:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/03/thames-triple-chaser/</guid>
      <description>Went for my second ride with the London Brompton Club today. Was a fairly long ride, the Thames Triple Chase - 25 miles or so from Central London out to Stratford, West Ham and then down across the river on the Woolwich ferry, down to the O2 and across on the cable car and then heading back towards London before crossing over finally into the Greenwich foot tunnel.
Well attended ride!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garmin Vivofit</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/03/garmin-vivofit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2014 11:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/03/garmin-vivofit/</guid>
      <description>Ok, so not strictly cycling related but it is general health, so I guess this can go here really!
Fitness Bands So I&amp;rsquo;m probably guilty of falling for marketing hype and getting some of the fitness devices. A few months back I&amp;rsquo;d purchased one of the body fat scales that&amp;rsquo;s also wi-fi enabled and records my weight (Fitbit Aria). Much to the amusement of my work colleagues!
Once I got that, I&amp;rsquo;d been considering a pedometer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Ride</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/03/sunday-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 07:24:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/03/sunday-ride/</guid>
      <description>This weekend saw me get out for a fairly short ride on the Brompton as I&amp;rsquo;m in the middle of moving house so couldn&amp;rsquo;t get out on Saturday and on Sunday, I only managed a quick ride before going to see a friend (though I did squeeze in some extra Km&amp;rsquo;s by having to cycle to the nearest tube station, rather than my local railway station as the trains are down for engineering works).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Ride in the Sun</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/03/a-ride-in-the-sun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 21:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/03/a-ride-in-the-sun/</guid>
      <description>So it seems like spring has finally come to the UK and that the sun has been shining all weekend. It&amp;rsquo;s made for some fantastic riding conditions.
Certainly makes a change from earlier in the year!
Remember the Creepy Tunnel Ride? Well, it&amp;rsquo;s looking a bit different down there now.


The water levels dropped so no getting my feet wet this time around around! The lights were working this time around as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loki Arrives</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/03/loki-arrives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2014 17:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/03/loki-arrives/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been off work ill for the start of the week - but during that time, I got a phone call I had been eagerly awaiting.
Evans rang me up on Tuesday lunchtime to tell me that my Brompton had arrived into store and that I could go and pick it up. Unfortunately, I had to wait until Thursday to go and collect it because I was still ill and didn&amp;rsquo;t want to sit in the office spreading it around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LBC London to Gatwick Ride</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/02/lbc-london-to-gatwick-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 11:03:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/02/lbc-london-to-gatwick-ride/</guid>
      <description>Went on my first ride with the London Brompton Club, though my Brompton hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet arrived.
Got the day going after a quick trip to the Kings Cross shops… nothing better to get the day started than a bacon bap with brown sauce! (Though probably not the best of foods to go cyclign with but it tastes good!)

I&amp;rsquo;d left my bike at the office over the weekend and so picked it up and changed before heading down to Embankment to meet the rest of the riders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking like a touring bike!</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/02/looking-like-a-touring-bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 18:25:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/02/looking-like-a-touring-bike/</guid>
      <description>So I&amp;rsquo;ve had the new bike for a while now and I&amp;rsquo;ve made a few changes to it since then. It&amp;rsquo;s actually now beginning to look like a touring bike!

A few things I already had lying around and I&amp;rsquo;ve added these to the bike, others have required a purchase. The changes I&amp;rsquo;ve made so far are:-
Saddle The saddle was the first change - in fairness, I changed this the day after I got the bike as my Charge Spoon is the comfiest saddle I&amp;rsquo;ve used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fire Engineering and Git</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/02/fire-engineering-and-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2014 21:20:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/02/fire-engineering-and-git/</guid>
      <description>As a geek, Git is a fantastic program. Almost everything I write is in plain text, outside of the office (where I&amp;rsquo;m forced to use Microsoft Word). I wrote my doctoral thesis within LaTeX and Git allowed me to keep a fantastic record of the changes to my thesis as I went through my work, as well as providing a backup. Outside of work, I write occasionally for Micro Mart and of course I write these blog posts and others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sun and Floods</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/02/sun-and-floods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 18:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/02/sun-and-floods/</guid>
      <description>Today was deceptively a nice day to go for a ride. The sun was out but there was still a biting wind out. However, I wanted to get out and about and the weather seemed to be decent enough so wrapping up warm, I headed out.
I fancied trying to cycle the Cole Green Way today but I thought with the rain we&amp;rsquo;ve had recently, this was probably not the wisest idea, as I know the other path nearby, the St Albans Way, has a section that floods in the rain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inaugural Ride</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/01/inaugural-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 18:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/01/inaugural-ride/</guid>
      <description>Not quite the inaugural ride I had planned for the end of January but hey, things don&amp;rsquo;t often go to plan. I&amp;rsquo;ve been informed that my new bike (as you might have guessed from the links on the blog, is a Brompton) will take a bit longer to manufacture (as it&amp;rsquo;s a custom build), so that will have to wait until next month.
I spent some time umm&amp;rsquo;ing and ahh&amp;rsquo;ing about getting rid of my road bike as whilst it&amp;rsquo;s been a good bike over the past year and a bit and we&amp;rsquo;ve cycled about 2,800Km together, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;m to keen on it anymore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creepy Tunnel Ride</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/01/creepy-tunnel-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 10:58:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/01/creepy-tunnel-ride/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s ride was another slow ride around the local area, to warm the legs up before trying to get back on the road bike. Was a fantastic day in terms of weather after the storms of last week and the week before that - that was seen in the number of people out on bikes. Went past quite a few club rides out on the roads.
Route consisted of some busy A roads around Cockfosters (which I&amp;rsquo;m not keen on and I think I&amp;rsquo;ll perhaps be avoiding in the future if I can), some quieter roads around Barnet and then a stretch along the NCN Route 12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling Gloves</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/01/cycling-gloves/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 08:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/01/cycling-gloves/</guid>
      <description>So a fairly boring blog post perhaps on gloves.
It&amp;rsquo;s very rare that you&amp;rsquo;ll catch me out on a bike without wearing gloves. Not 100% why but I also think it&amp;rsquo;s better to wear gloves as if I come off the bike, the first part of my body that I&amp;rsquo;ll move to try and stop myself probably is my hands. And considering I use them everyday, I kind of want them to not be to damaged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First ride of 2014</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/01/first-ride-of-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 20:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/01/first-ride-of-2014/</guid>
      <description>So it was my first ride of 2014 today. I&amp;rsquo;d been dying to get out on the bike, partly because of my new Garmin Edge 800 but also because I&amp;rsquo;d been planning a few rides and just hadn&amp;rsquo;t been able to shake off the flu I came down with on New Years Eve!
Anyhow, I managed to get out today. The idea was to get out and just go for a ride.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/01/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 18:18:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2014/01/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>So it&amp;rsquo;s a new year and I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that I&amp;rsquo;ll get back into blogging - it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten anything down so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give it a go - New Year, New Start and all that.
Anyhow, so as this year I&amp;rsquo;m looking to do some serious cycling, what better option to write on then?
So this is the start of a new blog that will be focussing on my riding for the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SARS - Small Array of Raspberry Pi&#39;s</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2013/11/sars-small-array-of-raspberry-pis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2013 21:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2013/11/sars-small-array-of-raspberry-pis/</guid>
      <description>SARS Background Ok, so not the Severe Acute Respiratory sort of SARS, but in fact a form of computer…
In fact, SARS is what I&amp;rsquo;ve nicknamed my new &amp;ldquo;supercomputer&amp;rdquo;. SARS stands for Small Array of Raspberry piS. I built this as I&amp;rsquo;ve also been interested in multi core computing, even before dual core and multi core chips were the norm (this is back in the pre-64 bit chips as well, when AMD Athlon chips were king!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ChromeOS is to Windows like Android was to iOS circa 2008</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2013/09/chromeos-is-to-windows-like-android-was-to-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 19:03:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2013/09/chromeos-is-to-windows-like-android-was-to-ios/</guid>
      <description>ChromeOS is to Windows like Android was to iOS circa 2008
I think this is a fairly accurate article.
It&amp;rsquo;ll be interesting to see where Chrome OS gets to in the future. Afterall, new Chromebooks have been announced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bittorrent Sync - An Overview</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2013/09/bittorrent-sync-an-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 17:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2013/09/bittorrent-sync-an-overview/</guid>
      <description>So I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Bittorrent Sync for a while now and thought I&amp;rsquo;d write some thoughts on it.
A brief description of it would be that it&amp;rsquo;s the sync elements of Dropbox, but running on your own server. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the web interface (but that can be added with third party applications, such as Owncloud) but does one thing, and one thing well.
Basics BTSync is advertised as server-less Dropbox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Day One</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2013/08/improving-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 19:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2013/08/improving-day-one/</guid>
      <description>Day One is a journalling app for iOS and OSX and is an great app for keeping track of things during the day - be that photos or text. It&amp;rsquo;s a great app and I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it, almost as long as I&amp;rsquo;ve been using a Mac. I love the fact that I can view and add enteries on all my iOS devices and my Mac and that the data storage format is open (it&amp;rsquo;s all XML files).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Content Found</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2013/08/ive-seen-a-lot-spoken-on-various-places-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2013 17:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2013/08/ive-seen-a-lot-spoken-on-various-places-online/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a lot spoken on various places online, such as MacStories and more recently in #iPadOnly, about Byword so I thought it was about time I give it a go, both on iOS and OSX as I&amp;rsquo;m a keen user of Markdown.
Byword Mac Byword focuses on simplicity and minimalism and offers you a blank screen to get started. Digging into the options lets you view the meagre amount of settings, something I was after.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chromebook and Plain Text</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2013/07/chromebook-and-plain-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 23:21:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2013/07/chromebook-and-plain-text/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had the Chromebook for a while and I&amp;rsquo;ve used it off and on over that time. A few niggles would creep in here and there, namely due to the offline access. Yet, this didn&amp;rsquo;t prove to be to problematic most of the time. It&amp;rsquo;s main use seemed to be as a second machine as the girlfriend would often use it when she was round to browse on, whilst I would use the iPad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chromebook Review</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2013/03/chromebook-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 14:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2013/03/chromebook-review/</guid>
      <description>So I’ve been using a Chromebook now for a few weeks and I thought I’d say a few words on it. I’ve seen it slated in various places because of what it is (basically a dumb terminal with access to the web). However, whilst that’s pretty apt, I thought I’d mention my thoughts on it.
Chromebook I purchased the Samsung Series 3 Chromebook, partly due to it’s similarities to the Macbook Air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2012 Summary</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/12/2012-12-31-2012-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 22:07:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/12/2012-12-31-2012-summary/</guid>
      <description>So this year has been a bit of an up and down ride. Though I can probably say that it&amp;rsquo;s been better than last year, though as I&amp;rsquo;ve felt the rollercoaster ride recently, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d sit down and do a summary of the year so I can see exactly what I&amp;rsquo;ve achieved.
Achievements   Getting a job, working for company I enjoy working for and enjoy what I&amp;rsquo;m doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boring (A Review)</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/11/boring-a-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 14:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/11/boring-a-review/</guid>
      <description>Boring (A Review)
 The mark of a great device is that it should just become sort of boring. A tool. One that is reliable. One that you just grab and use when you need it to perform the tasks for which it is built, and that you then put down satisfied that you have it even if you are no longer OMGing every time.  I think this just about sums up my iPad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Experiment</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/11/email-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 21:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/11/email-experiment/</guid>
      <description>My long standing dislike of emails (well, email software) is well known as I moan about it here and here. Well this came to a head this week again when I decided to slim down my hard drive due to boot camping again.
Part of this involved running JDiskReport to see what was taking up space. As part of this, I ended up moving my iPad to back up to iCloud and will then eventually remove all the apps from being kept on my machine (as that&amp;rsquo;s a fairly hefty 7GB - which adds up when you only have 320 to play with and you want at least 60 of that for Windows!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crappy Computers</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/11/crappy-computers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2012 12:03:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/11/crappy-computers/</guid>
      <description>Crappy Computers
So the sentiment that crappy computers are good enough for casual users is exactly backwards: casual users are the ones that need high-end computers, while proficient users are the ones who can work around the limitations of crappy computers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Email - A Holy Grail</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/10/markdown-email-a-holy-grail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 17:54:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/10/markdown-email-a-holy-grail/</guid>
      <description>Since I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered Markdown, I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to write everything in it (bar my thesis!). The code is so simple and make it so much easier to format text without having to revert to using a mouse, just to emphasise a specific piece of text. I switched to writing my notes in Evernote in Markdown, even though Evernote currently doesn&amp;rsquo;t support markdown in the (potentially vain) hope that they&amp;rsquo;ll implement it in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown - Syntax Missing</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/09/markdonn-syntax-missing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 21:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/09/markdonn-syntax-missing/</guid>
      <description>So coming to edit some Markdown notes on my iPad today and I come across one flaw. Don’t get me wrong, I love Markdown and my Markdown app of choice (Writing Kit) is fantastic, with Dropbox auto sync (every 10 key strokes) and built in web browser, it’s still missing something.
That something happens to be syntax highlighting. I didn’t realise how much I miss it until hitting it up on the iPad and missing the feeling I get when I see the different colour code such as when I open documents in Multimarkdown Editor on the mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musings on Engineering (Apple and Pi)</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/09/musings-on-engineering-apple-and-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 14:43:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/09/musings-on-engineering-apple-and-pi/</guid>
      <description>So I&amp;rsquo;ve now been a Mac owner for the past year and half, if not a little more and it&amp;rsquo;s caused me to be laughed at, ridiculed and insulted. I have thick skin, I can let that all go because you pay your money and take your choices in life. My choice was to go Mac. And I wanted to mention one reason why I went this way.
Engineering.
I&amp;rsquo;m an engineer - again, my specialism suggests to other general engineers that I&amp;rsquo;m not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ulysses Review</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/07/ulysses-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 20:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/07/ulysses-review/</guid>
      <description>So when I discovered Markdown, I quickly became a fan. The ease of creating content and not having to worry to much regarding the style of the content until after the writing was finished reminded me of LaTeX but allowed a much easier syntax to be used and it was also cross platform and compatible with Mac, Windows and iPad.
But as someone that writes a lot, not only for my work (try writing a thesis!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spideroak - Lion and Spideroak: A Few Niggles</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/06/spideroak-lion-and-spideroak-a-few-niggles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 10:05:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/06/spideroak-lion-and-spideroak-a-few-niggles/</guid>
      <description>So I&amp;rsquo;ve written before on my use of Spideroak. The service has proved to be a fantastic help and runs nicely in the background but I&amp;rsquo;ve hit a few snags using the program itself.
Going in to change the details of what’s being saved to the Spideroak servers, I find that the client gives me a lot of the “spinning beachball of death”

Ok, I don’t have to change the saved folders very often but like today where I decided to remove a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submitting a Springerlink/Elsvier Journal Using LaTeX and Editorial Manager</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/05/submitting-a-springerlinkelsvier-journal-using/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 16:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/05/submitting-a-springerlinkelsvier-journal-using/</guid>
      <description>So I ran into various issues this morning in trying to submit a journal to the Springerlink journal, Fire Technology.
As recommended by the journal, I was trying to submit my paper in LaTeX form. After all, I spent the time learning it for my thesis, might as well write the paper in it as well right? Yeah, especially as the Word template they provide is terrible and is a complete pain in the ass to use on a Mac (or a newer version of Office than it was designed for – so probably anything after 2003 by looks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrivener - Writers Software</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/04/scrivener-writers-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 18:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/04/scrivener-writers-software/</guid>
      <description>So I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying some new writing tools for the thesis. Possibly a bit late in the game now but I&amp;rsquo;m still writing other things for various reasons, for example the UKAPUnewsletter editor and I&amp;rsquo;ve written a few magazine articles for the UK weekly computer magazine Micro Mart and not to mention I&amp;rsquo;m still writing academic papers.
So when I learnt of Scrivener , I thought I best give it a go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moneywiz - iOS Personal Finance</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/03/moneywiz-ios-personal-finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 14:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/03/moneywiz-ios-personal-finance/</guid>
      <description>Is Moneywiz worth it? I&amp;rsquo;d say so. There we are, simple answer to a simple question.
However, those that don’t know what Moneywiz is might be scratching their heads at this point. What is it and why is it worth whatever it is?
Intro Moneywiz is an iPad and iPhone app from Silverwiz . It’s a personal finance app designed to be powerful but yet easy to use. Since I&amp;rsquo;ve got my iPad (and Mac), I&amp;rsquo;ve played with various personal finance apps but never found one I liked until now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally broke it!</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/03/finally-broke-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 18:32:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/03/finally-broke-it/</guid>
      <description>Now here’s something I never thought I&amp;rsquo;d ever be posting. Today I broke the 10Km barrier. Pushed it towards the end but managed to make it home in just over 10Km. A few aches and pains (I managed to get a blood blister on my toe and my shoes rubbed a little on the side of my right foot) but overall feeling pretty chuffed with that. Will have to try and carry it on but drop it to a sub 60 minute run if I can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zombies, Run!</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/03/zombies-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 18:42:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/03/zombies-run/</guid>
      <description>So I followed this app since I saw the Kickstarter page – I didn’t donate but I was quite happy to wait until the app arrived. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I did, it adds a bit of fun to my runs!
I tried it out today and got this as my first run.
Nothing fantastic but now I know how the app works, I&amp;rsquo;ll be turning on the Zombie Chases (basically HITT intervals!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPad Experiement - The Results</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/02/ipad-experiement-the-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 13:58:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/02/ipad-experiement-the-results/</guid>
      <description>Early Morning So the day didn’t get off to a good start really. Friday sees me paying some regular bills and moving some money around. Not an issue, I can easily check the payments using the Santander iPad/iPhone app. Easy. However, the problem comes in when I try and add it to my financial records. I keep these in GNUCash and with no iPad app, I&amp;rsquo;m stuck having to use the main desktop to enter the details in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPad Experiment</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/02/ipad-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 18:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/02/ipad-experiment/</guid>
      <description>Ok, so I&amp;rsquo;ve had the iPad for a while now and it’s been a great help to me for work. Just being able to mark up PDF papers (I read a lot of academic papers and the ability to highlight corrections etc in my thesis drafts is fantastic), keep a copy of my notes beside my Macbook screen and be a small, easy to use, portable device I can easily carry around, easier than my MBP is terrific.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reasons Why I Hate Email</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/02/reasons-why-i-hate-email/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 20:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/02/reasons-why-i-hate-email/</guid>
      <description>Email is a daily fact of life for most people. Whether it’s just getting the updates from web stores about special deals or swapping files for work, email plays a big part of our lives. And I&amp;rsquo;ve begun to hate it on the Mac.
This seems like an odd statement and especially as its aimed at just OS X and Apple. Don’t get me wrong, I use email a lot. It’s de facto communication method at work and I use Gmail and iCloud like others but I&amp;rsquo;ve begun to dread sending emails for a variety of reasons which I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Mac Apps I Can&#39;t Live Without</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/02/5-mac-apps-i-cant-live-without/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 22:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/02/5-mac-apps-i-cant-live-without/</guid>
      <description>So for the second part of my 5 items I can’t live without, I&amp;rsquo;m focussing on Mac applications. I use a Mac at home and at work (I&amp;rsquo;m lucky – basically I bought my work laptop myself!) so I&amp;rsquo;ve a fair few apps that I&amp;rsquo;ve tried for various tasks, both at home and work. However, the best tools will be the ones that are used in both locations.
 Alfred</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garmin Run</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/02/garmin-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 21:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/02/garmin-run/</guid>
      <description>First run with my Garmin strap for my Garmin 500. Uses the Garmin mounting kit for the Forerunner 201 and 301 (but actually fits the Gamrin 500 as well). Note that with the 500, the device runs down your arm, not perpendicular like a watch. Nothing major but something to consider.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blown Away by OS X Again</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/01/blown-away-by-os-x-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 18:34:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/01/blown-away-by-os-x-again/</guid>
      <description>So the Mac has managed to blow me away again today, almost as much as when I first started using it, about this time last year. How you might ask?
Well I found out today that you can create custom keyboard shortcuts.
As a self confessed keyboard lover (I love shortcuts and desktop launchers, like Alfred ), I really missed some of the keyboard shortcuts in Mail that others such as Sparrow and Postbox have, such as the ⌘ + Enter shortcut key to send email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garmin Going a Bit Mental...</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/01/garmin-going-a-bit-mental/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 16:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/01/garmin-going-a-bit-mental/</guid>
      <description>Seems my Garmin is going a bit mental – those altitudes are very much out and that heart rate, whilst it looks reasonable, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I hit 242 bpm!!
Time to sort out my bike and get back on that!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iTunes Match</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/01/itunes-match/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 19:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/01/itunes-match/</guid>
      <description>So I took the plunge this week and purchased iTunes Match. After using it for a bit, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d make a quick post about it.
Background iTunes Match is a cloud based music system built into iTunes and iOS devices that allow you to upload your music to iTunes servers and lets you download it to up to 10 iOS and OS X devices. It’s primarily a music storage service, rather than a streaming service like Spotify as when you listen to the song on an iOS device, it downloads the music to the device, whilst playing it as it downloads (streaming would then wipe it from the device to clear space, this doesn’t).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX to RTF</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/01/latex-to-rtf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2012 15:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/01/latex-to-rtf/</guid>
      <description>So for a while, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using LaTeX to write up my work but every now and then someone wants a copy of my work in Word so they can edit it or mark it up and they cant use a PDF editor. This means converting my PDF into a Word document or my LaTeX file into a RTF document.
The PDF route was probably the easiest as everything was nicely laid out already and set out as it should be and various services on the web manage to convert PDF’s relatively well to Word documents such as Zamzar However, the LaTeX to RTF option is also a possibility using the linux2rtf program however, that seems to be awkward at the best of times and annoyingly problematic at times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DuckDuckGo Stickers</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/01/duckduckgo-stickers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 14:45:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/01/duckduckgo-stickers/</guid>
      <description>So I blogged about Duck Duck Go earlier last year. See it here. I&amp;rsquo;m still using it as it’s a great search engine and I want others to know about it – it doesn’t have to be all about Google! So far I&amp;rsquo;ve only posted online but it&amp;rsquo;ll be easier to get more people interested now as they&amp;rsquo;ve just announced a Stickermule store here . My favourites probably have to be the Tesla and the John McCarthy ones.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
