<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Smart watch on Voxcaster</title>
    <link>http://vox.me.uk/tags/smart-watch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Smart watch on Voxcaster</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 08:22:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://vox.me.uk/tags/smart-watch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Garmin Venu 2 Review</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2022/02/garmin-venu-2-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 08:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2022/02/garmin-venu-2-review/</guid>
      <description>When I saw this announced by Garmin, I knew that it was something that I’d be interested in. I’ve flip flopped between Garmin and the Apple Watch over the last two years, often coming back to my Garmin Instinct Solar (and the non solar version before that). However, the reason for going back and testing the Apple Watch was for the onboard Siri support - being able to turn lights on and off in the house with my voice is handy, as well as the occasional quick text message or receiving a phone call whilst my phone is in my bike bag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garmin Vivoactive</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/09/garming-vivoactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 23:42:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2015/09/garming-vivoactive/</guid>
      <description>Background I never used to be a watch person, though that all change when I started running when at Loughborough and then when I moved to London and was at the mercy of trains (and meetings), I found a watch to be something I couldn&amp;rsquo;t leave behind.
For years, I used a classic - the Casio F-91W.
Not only was it bombproof (though, perhaps the wrong word to use there considering that owning one of the watches in Afghanistan was apparently enough to cause the Americans to detain you for questioning as it was often the watch used for detonators!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
