<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Markdown on Voxcaster</title>
    <link>http://vox.me.uk/tags/markdown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Markdown on Voxcaster</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 15:30:38 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://vox.me.uk/tags/markdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bear for Blogging</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/10/bear-for-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 15:30:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/10/bear-for-blogging/</guid>
      <description>I had ditched Ulysses when it went subscription but during 2020, I’d paid for the subscription as I’d managed to get a discount code for it. It was good to be able to use it across my devices and it’s still one of the best plain text editors in my view - however, I don’t view it as being worth almost £50 a year - consider that Microsoft charge £60 for Office plus storage space, whereas Ulysses makes use of iCloud space to sync, so I’m not even paying them for syncing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspire Continued</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/10/inspire-continued/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 20:58:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/10/inspire-continued/</guid>
      <description>After some further experimentation and use, I’ve a few more comments on Inspire Writer. I have been initially impressed with the Windows Ulysses clone. My initial review was written in it and was written using the 10 day free trial period. I purchased the software after using it for a day on the Windows Store - so I’ve been using the Microsoft Store version. There is a stand alone version available as well, though I would hope that there is feature parity between the two.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Journaling</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/10/markdown-journaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 16:41:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/10/markdown-journaling/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been journaling now for years. I started off using Day One for iOS and macOS. However, after this updated to the second version and moved to a subscription model, I decided that I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to pay for it, and moved. Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Zim Wiki for my journaling.
This has generally served me well, and ran nicely on Windows and Linux1. It worked and the output was portable and under my control, as each page is a text file and displays images inline.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
