<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>apple on Voxcaster</title>
    <link>http://vox.me.uk/tags/apple/</link>
    <description>Recent content in apple on Voxcaster</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 18:59:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://vox.me.uk/tags/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>M1 Mac Mini</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/01/m1-mac-mini/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 18:59:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2021/01/m1-mac-mini/</guid>
      <description>After the issues I’ve had previously with the Mac, I wasn’t sure I was going to get another Mac. But I did.
I watched the M1 release keynote after it had finished and was impressed with what I saw. If it was true. However, after hanging around the Mac Power Users forum, I’d seen some interesting Mac apps that I fancied giving a go - things like Hook. I also wanted to continue using Photos, as I hadn’t really found an alternative on Windows that really matched it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pixel 3a vs IPhone SE</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/10/pixel-3a-vs-iphone-se/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 18:36:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/10/pixel-3a-vs-iphone-se/</guid>
      <description>So, the iPhone SE was re-released, perhaps as a way for Apple to compete with the cheaper Android devices out there. Google started something similar last year with the release of the Pixel 3a - a cheaper, less powerful version of the Pixel 3.
I&amp;rsquo;ve tried both phones - I own the Pixel 3a and my wife has the iPhone SE 2020, so thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a quick review.
Camera The Pixel series is known for its camera, and the iPhone has always been well regarded for its camera - with Apple pushing the camera features heavily in various advertising.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Watch Background</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/07/apple-watch-background/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 11:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/07/apple-watch-background/</guid>
      <description>Apple Watch Faces I’ve been playing around with some Apple Watch faces recently - normally I would use a Modular Infographic face or at least one with a number of complications. However, I saw this one which I thought was a bit of fun.
As I’m going through a Star Wars phase again at the minute, I thought this was a good one.
I found the original artist here where you can download the image yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issues With MacOS</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/06/issues-with-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 08:42:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2020/06/issues-with-macos/</guid>
      <description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been running in to issues with macOS that I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to resolve and it&amp;rsquo;s beginning to annoy me no end.
Startup I&amp;rsquo;d been running in to startup issues for a week or so - the Mac would boot up and I would see the Apple logo on screen with the loading bar.
However, the screen would then go blank and I would only see the mouse cursor if I wriggled it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moneywiz - iOS Personal Finance</title>
      <link>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/03/moneywiz-ios-personal-finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 14:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vox.me.uk/post/2012/03/moneywiz-ios-personal-finance/</guid>
      <description>Is Moneywiz worth it? I&amp;rsquo;d say so. There we are, simple answer to a simple question.
However, those that don’t know what Moneywiz is might be scratching their heads at this point. What is it and why is it worth whatever it is?
Intro Moneywiz is an iPad and iPhone app from Silverwiz . It’s a personal finance app designed to be powerful but yet easy to use. Since I&amp;rsquo;ve got my iPad (and Mac), I&amp;rsquo;ve played with various personal finance apps but never found one I liked until now.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
